the idea here is really to uh...
understand what are those common
fundamental drivers
that we see
in our financial crises and banking
crises
how can we diagnose them before castro
so that&#39;s our
that&#39;s our that surge and then again
after each of these major
uh... later topics will have some up
will have some some exercises
to review the learning
democrats traverse uh... we&#39;re seeing
very very common drivers across all the
major
enough about crises uh...
and um...
there are
ways of predicting
uh... diagnosing them that are very
useful to find
uh... and we&#39;ll talk about uh... the
difference between black swan events
and out what time
uh... did use on that whose uh...
geologist calls a dragon case that&#39;s an
interesting discussion about exogenous
uh... versus indulge in this risks
uh... outlines as early-warning signals
uh... are are very very important that
universal
signal that something
either uh...
units various data or all something
really important has happened the
distribution has shifted
and will show you how to umkc
interpret some of those signals
so let&#39;s dive into systemic risk drivers
banking crises
followed very similar to jack trips
uh... they are are generally driven by
first surges in international capital
flow
uh... and uh...
an increase in asset prices
fueled by uh... liquidity
or credits
and this is a study from montana road
often dot com reinhart&#39;s com
banking crisis in equal opportunity
manus
and um...
it shows that sort of the proportion of
economies going through a banking crisis
and you can see that time
you know uh... quite often we can get to
uh... you anywhere from
fifteen uh... percent or more
of the world economy and the weighted
basis is in some kind of a banking
crisis a banking crisis or actually
fairly
fairly common there was a big stretch
after the war when we didn&#39;t have any
right whiskey of a spur of the illusion
that uh... maybe on you know
banking crisis had been solved
uh... but obviously they&#39;ve come back
out with a vengeance uh... so you can
see these these pics pikes here
uh... that&#39;s over close to forty percent
of the world economy
uh... being in a banking crisis
we seeing someone drivers in emerging
markets and uh... developed markets com
uh... and uh... financial centers are
uh... especially vulnerable
another interesting correlation
is that financial liberalization capital
mobility
tend to have a destabilizing effect
so uh... this is a chart here at that
time
roll-off quotes
which essentially shows uh... where
they&#39;re plotting their ranking financial
liberalization on the on the on on the
reds um... the red chart
and uh... and a m actually banking
crises okay uh... some of countries in
banking crisis
and you can see that there&#39;s a
relationship when there is a enough when
liberalization is going up
uh... banking crises tend to uh...
tend to uh... ten to spike thereafter
and i&#39;m quite often this is the case of
sort of uh... process of deregulation
uh... while uh... uh... as well of
having more lax supervision
so this is again
one of the one of the themes that we
clearly song and the movement more
recent um...
maurice in crisis
terms of foreign capital inflows it&#39;s
interesting to look at that say the u_s_
internet bubble here
foreign capital into equities had peaked
with internet bubble
foreign foreign uh... kaplan two
fixed-income markets peaked with the
credit a bubble
uh... and so that
that uh... that surgeon international
apple was certainly a functioned
of the sub-prime
crisis in the united states
we&#39;re having our own
obvious that problem around the world
increased levels of debt to g_d_p_
uh... the united states some
exceeded three hundred percent total
debt to g_d_p_ and two thousand three
and it&#39;s been going up
uh... pretty much
uh... in the entire developed world and
so that&#39;s uh...
unprecedented level of debt that we need
to
understand how to resolve
and there are three ways to
really resolved that crisis
uh... the first is through economic
growth
and uh...
you know hopefully they&#39;ll be strong
economic growth but um...
they rob you know but uh... historical
studies really show that some
uh... strong economic growth falling
uh... these kinds of prices tend to be
quite rare
big mckinsey study
i think from analyzing something like
pop thirty eight crises they found that
in only three cases
uh... have uh... you know economies
bounce back
very strongly after a banking crisis
and in each case case those quite unique
and ah... the nigerian puget that was
due to
uh...
thus covering a lot of or else
oil wealth
and the united states so that the
postwar effect uh... was essentially
about uh... well u_s_ you know as the
war dividend or the peace dividend
u_s_ was the only industrialized economy
left with manufacturing capabilities
sold uh... much more common posse is
going to be
uh... area
a decade or so of up
uh... sub par economic
and credit growth
uh... and of course will be a long
stretch for the united states which
uh... really since uh... the internet
bubble popped
in two thousand
you know really hasn&#39;t shown
signs of sustainable strong
growth right so if we look at
though did that
blue
bars or g_d_p_ has reported but somber
bread bars are just it by the mortgage
equity withdrawals
essentially what people took out
using using there are a bit their
housing as as banks
and uh... which really wanted to fueling
uh... discretionary spending if you took
out mortgage equity withdrawals you&#39;ll
see that ah... essentially from the dot
com bust
uh... to uh... the housing uh... crisis
that has been no economic growth so
essentially the united states is flat
line
in terms of economic growth for a deck
for well over a decade already
and sensor twelve years of arm
you know very very low
uh... growth
uh... so um... you know some of us
having phone sex with someone who said
that uh... i think we&#39;re
uh... we&#39;re going to face something
someone is the as a as japan
you know uh... decades of uh... slow
kind of growth while
in the way the u_s_ has already been
considered
uh... a decade of that
that the second
mort severe
uh... papas inflation
which is
uh... quite common
uh... as well
and uh... the most extreme
uh... would be a currency the valuation
followed by a credit default so those
are sort of
three archetypal
palce uh... that we need to be able to
look at in terms of
creating test scenarios that we
uh... we&#39;re going to look at the stress
testing
quote from conroe graphing
by guaranteeing everything
uh... the governments have transformed
the financial crisis into debt
crisis who guarantees the government&#39;s
that&#39;s seven two thousand nine
uh... and obviously we&#39;re now dealing
with the sovereign crisis